VINCENT RAMOS

Address

134 W. Devanah St. Covina, CA 91706

 Tel
 213.663.8296

 Email
 vram1980@gmail.com

 Linkedin
 https://linkedin.com/in/vram1980/

Website www.vincent-ramos.com

Profile

Software engineer specializing on the client side. I build things using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript. I've worked with teams big and small to deliver successful projects within an agile setting against impossible deadlines. Currently in love with SPA frameworks such as AngularJS and React. I love what I do and am constantly trying to do better.

I have worked on websites for the likes of Lexus, ABC, FX Networks, Vizio, Microsoft and Media Temple.

Experience

Bluebeam Inc.

Senior Web Developer, Pasadena, CA - May 2016 - Present

Senior Web Developer overseeing all things http://shop.bluebeam.com and https://shop.bluebeam.com/ from a UI development perspective. Duties include architect and build new pages and features for marketing campaigns with full global localization. Work with UX designers and implement and update new features on our web store as well as front end development and integration on our licensing portal for existing customers. Notable projects include full redesign of our main site. Redesigned web store and updated licensing portal using new reporting API's.

Media Temple

Front-End Architect, Los Angeles, CA - September 2014 - May 2016

Front End Engineer specializing in internal and customer facing web applications. Duties include architect and develop end to end web applications for existing and new customers within the customer account center. Projects include updated web file manager. One click app installation for WordPress, Drupal, etc. Also created new admin panels for new product launches.

HUGE

Senior Developer, Los Angeles, CA - July 2012 - September 2014

Senior Developer specializing in front end development. Duties include design and develop HTML/CSS/JS stack for premier websites as well as mentor junior developers. Projects include GIA, FX Networks, Lexus and Salesforce.

BLITZ

Senior Web Developer Santa Monica, CA - June 2011 - July 2012

Technical lead, working with front-end engineers across various functional teams. My primary role is to organize and evangelize in-house standards and best practices for client-side technologies, as they are applied in desktop, browsers, mobile web apps, and iOS devices. Project highlights include: BLITZ portfolio site, Saints Row: The Third, Naked Juice, and associated Facebook applications.

HUGE

Front End Developer Los Angeles, CA - June 2009 - June 2011

Front end developer for global digital agency. Project highlights include: Pepsi Refresh Project, ABC, CSpire, Houselogic, AnnArbor.com, Golf Channel.

VINCENT RAMOS

Address

134 W. Devanah St. Covina, CA 91706

Tel 213.663.8296

Email vram1980@gmail.com

Linkedin https://linkedin.com/in/vram1980/
Website www.vincent-ramos.com

C73 Media

Senior Designer Glendale, CA - Apr 2008 - Apr 2009

Senior designer for young web startup. Duties included oversee all creative aspects of projects and coordinate with programmers on site structure and layout. Front end coding was solely produced by me, from CSS to Jquery.

American Apparel

Senior Web Designer Los Angeles, CA - Nov 2007 - Apr 2008

Senior Web Designer for international garment dealer. The position demanded a keen eye for clear information design, typography, and user experience. Working together with production managers I was responsible for developing wire frames, designs, CSS libraries, DOM effects, for .NET, Ecommerce, Intranet, and various landing pages.

Education

The Art Institute of California - Los Angeles

Bachelor's Degree - Interactive Media Design - 2003

Skills

HTML5/XHTML, CSS2.1/CSS3, JavaScript/Ajax, React, Angular, jQuery, HTML5 Boilerplate, Bootstrap, Modernizr, CSS Grids, CSS Frameworks/Resets, Progressive Enhancement/ Graceful Degradation, Responsive Design, UX/Usability, Website Speed/Performance, Debugging Tools (Firebug, etc.), Mobile Web Development, Mobile Web Performance, Gestures, Cross-Browser/Cross-Platform Development, Document Object Model (DOM), Cross-Browser Bugs and Inconsistencies (primarily IE6-8), CSS Pre-Processors (LESS/Sass/Stylus), Git, HTML5 APIs (Canvas, Geolocation, Video, etc.), Templating (jtmpl, underscore, smarty), Accessibility, HTML/SS3 Polyfills, CMS (WordPress, Drupal, Joomla), Data Formats (e.g. JSON, XML), Internationalization/Localization, Offline Web Apps, Image Editing Tools (Photoshop, Fireworks, etc.), Web Font Embedding, SEO Basics, Haml, CoffeeScript